Register of the Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers, 1913-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, c.1933-1972 (Box 16-36)
  - "Debatte um Carl von Ossietzky," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 18: 9, Reel 22)
  - "Delitos y drogas en las Estados Unidos," (Crime and drugs in the US), Boletin informativo, Printed copy., October 1971. (Reel 22, Folder 18: 10)
  - "Das demographische Gesicht der Vereinigten Staaten hat sich geaendert," (US demography has changed), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., October 14, 1970. (Reel 22, Folder 18: 11)
  - "Die Demokraten behaupten ihre Kongress-mehrheit, Analyse der 1970er Wahlen," (The Democrats assert their congressional majority, analysis of the 1970 elections), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copies., November 11, 1970. (Folder 18: 12, Reel 22)
  - "Demokraten brauchen ein Wunder," (Democrats need a miracle), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 9, 1968. (Folder 18: 13, Reel 22)
  - "Die Demokraten haben schwere Sorgen," (The Democrats have serious difficulties), Vorwaerts, Typescript and printed copy., March 5, 1970. (Folder 18: 14, Reel 22)
  - "Denk ich an Deutschland in der Nacht," (When I think about Germany at night), Freiheit und Recht, Printed copies., November 1965. (Folder 18: 15, Reel 22)
  - "Die deutsch-juedische Symbiose," (The German Jewish symbiosis), Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copies., September 13, 1968. (Folder 18: 16, Reel 22)
  - "Die deutsch-juedische und deutsch-israelische Problematik," (The German-Jewish and German-Israeli problem), Typescript. (Folder 18: 17, Reel 22)
  - "Der Deutsche Bundestag und die Wiedergut-machung," (The German parliament and restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 245, 1961. (Folder 18: 18, Reel 22)
  - "Deutsche Fluechtlinge nach 1933," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 18: 19, Reel 22)
  - "Die deutsche Kleinstadt heute," (The German small town today), Aufbau, Printed copies., February 25, 1966. (Folder 18: 20, Reel 22)
  - "Deutsche leisten freiwillige Wiedergutmachung," (Germans are accomplishing voluntary restitution), Aufbau, Printed copies., May 6, 1966. (Folder 18: 21, Reel 22)
  - "Die deutsche Propaganda gegen Polen," Die Zukunft, Printed copy., March 17, 1939. (Folder 18: 22, Reel 22)
  - "Deutsche Werke fuer Amerikaner, das Goethe-Haus in New York," Printed copy., March 18, 1961. (Reel 22, Folder 18: 23)
  - "Die Deutschen und die Amerikaner," Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 22, Folder 18: 24)
  - "Ein deutscher Patriot," Westfaelische Rundschau, Printed copy., May 4, 1963. (Reel 22, Folder 18: 25)
  - "Deutschlands geistiger Verlust ist Amerikas Gewinn," (Germany's intellectual loss is America's gain), Holograph and typescript., c. 1960. (Reel 22, Folder 18: 26)
  - "Die fuer die Menschlichkeit ihr Leben gaben" (Those who gave their lives for humanity), research materials, including correspondence, Typescript, mimeographed, and printed material., June 1969. (Reel 22, Reel 23, Folder 18: 27-29)
  - "El Dilema Norteamericano," Boletin informativo, Printed copy., November 1968. (Folder 18: 30, Reel 23)
  - "Doch einseitiger Truppenrueckzug?" (Unilateral troop withddrawal after all?) Tagwacht, Printed copy, May 20, 1969. (Folder 18: 31, Reel 23)
  - "Does German Jewry have a Future?" The Jewish Digest, Printed copy., 1962. (Folder 18: 32, Reel 23)
  - "Dokumente des Friedens in Swarthmore," (Documents of peace at Swarthmore), New Yorker Staatszeitung, Printed copy., November 17, 1950. (Folder 18: 33, Reel 23)
  - "Die Dollarkrise--hat John V. Lindsay eine Chance?" Typescript (carbon copy)., August 17, 1971. (Folder 18: 34, Reel 23)
  - "Der dornige Weg vor dem Austausch von Botschaftern zwischen der Bundesrepublik und Israel," (The thorny road ahead of the exchange of embassadors between West Germany and Israel), Rheinischer Merkur, Reprint., April 30, 1965. (Folder 18: 35, Reel 23)
  - "Drama des Chicagoer Aufruhrprozesses," (The drama of the Chicago demonstration trial), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copies., February 27, 1970. (Folder 18: 36, Reel 23)
  - "Drei entscheidende Beschluesse," (Three decisive decisions), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., March 26, 1969. (Folder 18: 37, Reel 23)
  - "Dem dritten Weltkrieg entgegen? Luci Johnsons kleine Moenche und U Thants Warnungen," (Toward the Third World War? Luci Johnson's little monks and U Thant's warnings), Vorwaerts, Printed copies., May 25, 1967. (Reel 23, Folder 18: 38)
  - "Durch irrige Rechtsprechung Zutreiberdienste fuer kommunistische Laender," (Mistaken legal judgments benefit communist countries), Typescript (carbon copy)., 1967. (Folder 18: 39, Reel 23)
  - "Die Durchfuehrung des Bundesrueckerstattungs-gesetzes," (The implementation of the West German restitution law), Aufbau, Printed copy., May 25, 1962. (Folder 18: 40, Reel 23)
  - "Duestere Zukunft der USA," (Dim future for US Tagwacht, Printed copy., November 19, 1968. (Folder 18: 41, Reel 23)
  - "Echo auf die Schaeffer-Rede," (Echo of the Schaeffer speech), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 3, 1958. (Reel 23, Folder 18: 42)
  - "Edward Kennedys politische Zukunft gefaehrdet?" (E.K.'s political future in jeopardy?), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 23, Folder 18: 43)
  - "Edward Kennedys Rueckzugsgefechte," (E.K.'s retreating battles), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copies., September 13, 1969. (Reel 23, Folder 18: 44)
  - "Ehemalige Berliner Juden ueberreichen der Berliner Juedischen Gemeinde Festschrift," (Former Berlin Jews present commemorative book to the Berlin Jewish community), Typescript and carbon copy. (Reel 23, Folder 18: 45)
  - "Ehepaar Rosenberg in der Todeszelle," (Rosenbergs on death row), Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Printed copy., January 3, 1953. (Reel 23, Folder 18: 46)
  - Die Ehrenschuld, reviews. Printed copies., 1967-1968. (Reel 23, Folder 18: 47-48)
  - "Die Ehrenschuld muss getilgt werden. Warum Massenversammlung am 2. Mai," (Moral debt must be paid. Why a mass meeting on May 2, Aufbau, Printed copy., April 23, 1965. (Reel 23, Folder 19: 1)
  - "800,000 Jews are in need," Mimeographed copy., January 9, 1948. (Folder 19: 2, Reel 23)
  - "$1.76 Monatsrente fuer zwei Naziopfer," ($1.76 monthly pension for 2 Nazi victims) Die Wiedergutmachung, Printed copy., 1965. (Folder 19: 3, Reel 23)
  - "Ein Jahr nach dem deutsch-juedischen Wiedergutmachungsabkommen," (One year after the German-Jewish restitution treaty), Mimeographed copy., n.d. (Folder 19: 4, Reel 23)
  - "Einaeugige Justiz in USA." (One eyed justice in the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 8, 1970. (Folder 19: 5, Reel 23)
  - "Eindruecke von einer Studienreise durch Deutschland," (Impressions of a study trip through Germany), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 23, 1960. (Folder 19: 6, Reel 23)
  - "Die Eingliederung in die Vereinigten Staaten," (Assimilation into the US), Typescript (carbon copy)., August 6, 1962. (Reel 23, Folder 19: 7)
  - "Einloesung der Ehrenschuld, Vortrag von Martin Hirsch," (Payment of the debt of honor, lecture by M.H.), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 22, 1966. (Reel 23, Folder 19: 8)
  - "Der einsame Nixon," (Lonely Nixon), Tagwacht, Printed copy., January 25, 1969. (Reel 23, Folder 19: 9)
  - "Das Einstein Haus in Ulm," Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., December 10, 1969. (Folder 19: 10, Reel 23)
  - Emigration: Geschichte der Hitler-Fluechtlinge 1933-1945. Undated, annotated typescript drafts and related material. Final form was published in Frankfurt, Europaeische Verlagsanstalt, 1969.
    - Outline. (Reel 23, Folder 19: 11)
    - Draft A.
      - Introduction and Contents (Reel 23, Folder 19: 12)
      - Chapter 1. (Reel 23, Folder 19: 13)
      - Chapter 2. (Reel 24, Folder 19: 14)
      - Chapter 3. (Folder 19: 15, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 4. (Folder 19: 16, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 5. (Folder 19: 17, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 6. (Folder 19: 18, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 7-8. (Folder 19: 19, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 9 (Folder 19: 20, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 12. (Folder 19: 21, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 13. (Folder 19: 22, Reel 24)
      - Part IV. (Folder 19: 23, Reel 24)
      - Chapter 19. (Reel 24, Folder 19: 24)
      - Chapter 20. (Reel 24, Folder 19: 25)
      - Appendix. (Folder 19: 26, Reel 24)
    - Draft B.
      - Part I, copy 1. (Reel 24, Folder 19: 27)
      - Part I, copy 2. (Reel 25, Folder 20: 1)
      - Part II, copy 1. (Reel 25, Folder 20: 2)
      - Part II, copy 2. (Reel 25, Folder 20: 3)
      - Part III, copy 1. (Folder 20: 4, Reel 25)
      - Part III, copy 2. (Folder 20: 5, Reel 25)
      - Part IV, copy 1. (Folder 20: 6, Reel 25)
      - Part IV, copy 2. (Folder 20: 7, Reel 25)
      - Part V, copy 1. (Reel 25, Folder 20: 8)
      - Part V, copy 2. (Reel 25, Folder 20: 9)
      - Part VI. (Folder 20: 10, Reel 25)
      - Appendix. (Folder 20: 11, Reel 25)
      - Bibliography. (Reel 25, Folder 20: 12)
    - Galley proofs.
      - Copy 1. (Folder 21: 1, Reel 26)
      - Copy 2. (Folder 21: 2, Reel 26)
      - Copy 3. (Reel 26, Folder 21: 3)
    - Page proofs. (Reel 27, Folder 21: 4)
    - Prospectus. (Folder 21: 5, Reel 27)
    - Publicity. (Reel 27, Folder 21: 6)
    - Reviews., 1968-1969 (Reel 27, Folder 21: 7)
    - Reviews., 1969-1971 (Folder 22: 1-5, Reel 27)
    - Miscellaneous drafts. (Reel 27, Folder 22: 6-8, Reel 28)
    - Miscellaneous drafts. (Folder 23: 1-3, Reel 29, Reel 28)
    - Miscellaneous research material. (Folder 23: 4-10, Reel 29, Reel 30)
  - "Das Ende der internationalen Fluechtlings-organisation," (The end of the international refugee organization), Typescript (carbon copies). (Folder 24: 1, Reel 30)
  - "Das Ende der juedischen Einheitsgemeinde Berlin," (The end of the unified Jewish community in Berlin), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 20, 1953. (Folder 24: 2, Reel 30)
  - "Ende des Vietnamkrieges in Sicht," (End of the Viet Nam war in sight), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 12, 1969. (Folder 24: 3, Reel 30)
  - "Das Ende einer Hoffnung," (The end of a hope), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., June 13, 1968. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 4)
  - "England will helfen, London an der Spitze der Rettungsaktion," (England intends to help, London at the head of the rescue action), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 12, 1943. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 5)
  - "Entdeckt Amerika den Frieden?" (Is America discovering peace?), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., February 16, 1967. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 6)
  - "Die Entlassung des Innenminister Walter Hickel," (Dismissal of W.H.), Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 7, 1970. (Folder 24: 7, Reel 30)
  - "Entry Limited," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., February 7, 1949. (Folder 24: 8, Reel 30)
  - "Entschaedigung fuer die Nutzniesser der Naziverfolgung," (Restitution for the beneficiaries of the Nazi persecution), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 19, 1964. (Folder 24: 9, Reel 30)
  - "Entschaedigungsprobleme in Montreal," (Restitution problems in M.), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 8, 1961. (Folder 24: 10, Reel 30)
  - "Das Entschaedigungswerk in Zahlen," (restitution work in numbers), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 3, 1966. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 11)
  - "Entspricht der Krieg in Vietnam dem Gesetz?" (Does the war in Viet Nam conform to the law?), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 12)
  - "Enttaeuschung, nach Nixons Vietnam Rede" (Disappointment after Nixon's Viet Nam speech), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 24: 13, Reel 30)
  - "Epoche der Furcht in USA," (Epoch of fear in the US), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., November 3, 1970. (Folder 24: 14, Reel 30)
  - "Erbe von John L. Lewis wankt," (Heritage of J.L.L. falters), Tagwacht, Printed copy., March 20, 1970. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 15)
  - "Erhoehung der laufenden Entschaedigungsrenten," (Increase in current resitution payments), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 11, 1966. (Folder 24: 16, Reel 30)
  - "Erich Schatzki, 70 Jahre," Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., January 26, 1968. (Folder 24: 17, Reel 30)
  - "Erinnerung an einen Polizeipraesidenten," (Memory of a police chief), Stuttgarter Zeitung, Printed copy., August 18, 1951. (Folder 24: 18, Reel 30)
  - "Erinnerungstag 1971!" (Memorial Day 1971), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., June 11, 1971. (Folder 24: 19, Reel 30)
  - "Ernest Mosevius, 17 Jahre," Aufbau, Printed copy., December 18, 1964. (Folder 24: 20, Reel 30)
  - "Ernst H. Weismann, 60 Jahre," Aufbau, Printed copy., March 3, 1961. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 21)
  - "Der erste Streik gegen die Regierung," (The first strike against the government), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 30, Folder 24: 22)
  - "Erweiterung des Haushaltssicherungsgesetzes auf Rueckerstattung?", (Extension of the economic stabilizing law to indemnification?), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 30, Folder 24: 23)
  - "Es begann schon bei Truman..." (It already began with T.), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 22, 1971. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 24)
  - "Es ist etwas faul im Staate-Mitchells," (Something is rotten in the state of Mitchell), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., July 14, 1971. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 25)
  - "Ein Exempel wird statuiert, Black Panther Fuehrer Bobby Seal wird wegen Beleidigung des Gerichts vier Jahre eingesperrt," (An example is established, Black Panther leader B. S. is sentenced to four years for contempt of court), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., November 27, 1969. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 26)
  - "Die Exilsituation in den Vereinigten Staaten," (The exil situation in the US), Typescript (carbon copies). (Folder 24: 27, Reel 30)
  - "Existiert ein innerjuedischer Wiedergutmachungskoflikt?" (Is there a conflict about restitution among Jews?), Mimeographed copies., n.d. (Folder 24: 28, Reel 30)
  - "Expraesident Johnson erhebt wieder seine Stimme, Ernuechterung ueber Nixon," (Former President Johnson again raises his voice, sobering thoughts about Nixon), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., November 24, 1971. (Folder 24: 29, Reel 30)
  - "Die Expropriation der Juden im Dritten Reich," (The expropriation of the Jews in the Third Reich), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 10, 1967. (Folder 24: 30, Reel 30)
  - "Die Extremen in den Vereinigten Staaten," (The extremes in the US), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 24: 31, Reel 30)
  - "Falke und Taube zugleich," (Hawk and dove at the same time), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., July 15, 1971. (Folder 24: 32, Reel 30)
  - "Ein falsches Geschichts-Urteil," (A false historical judgment), Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Printed copy., March 31, 1959. (Folder 24: 33, Reel 30)
  - "Fanny Wurmbrand, 80 Jahre," Aufbau, Printed copies., July 26, 1968. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 34)
  - "Die faschistische Bewegung in U.S.A.," (The fascist movement in the US), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 29, 1943. (Folder 24: 35, Reel 30)
  - "Das finanzielle und politische Dilemma," Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 6, 1971. (Folder 24: 36, Reel 30)
  - "Flucht oder Emigration - 1933-1938," (Flight or emigration), speech, Typescript and related material., January 19, 1972. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 37)
  - "Fluechtlinge-wichtiges Kampfpotential," (Refugees-important combat potential), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 11, 1941. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 38)
  - "Das Fluechtlingsproblem zwischen den zwei Weltkriegen," (The refugee problem between the two world wars), Typescript (carbon copy) and related material. (Reel 30, Folder 24: 39)
  - "Die Folgen der Moerderkugel von Memphis," (The consequences of the bullet of M.), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., August 31, 1971. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 40)
  - "Forderungen der Claims Conference fuer das Wiedergutmachungs-Schlussgesetz," (Demands of the C.C. for the final restitution law), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 6, 1962. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 41)
  - "The Forgotten Allies," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 42)
  - "Forgotten People," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., February 27, 1948. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 43)
  - "Four Fallacies of the Fuchs Case," Printed copy., n.d. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 44)
  - "Die Frage der Lokalitaet," (The question of locality), Aufbau, Printed copies., December 22, 1967. (Folder 24: 45, Reel 31)
  - "Frankreich Ja--Pompidou Nein," (France yes--Pompidou no), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 46)
  - "Franz Boehm: An Appreciation," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., May 23, 1955. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 47)
  - "Freund der Verfolgten in schwerer Not," (Friend of the persecuted in severe distress), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., February 25, 1972. (Folder 24: 48, Reel 31)
  - "Frieden mit bewusstem Risiko: William Rogers und Averell Harriman," (Peace with a conscious risk), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., September 5, 1969. (Folder 24: 49, Reel 31)
  - "Friedenspraesident Nixon," (Peace president Nixon), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., October 19, 1970. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 50)
  - "Friedrich Janz," Aufbau, Printed copy., February 7, 1964. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 51)
  - "Fritz Kuester," Aufbau, Printed copy., May 6, 1966. (Folder 24: 52, Reel 31)
  - "From Countries of Persecution to Safety," Typescript (carbon copies)., n.d. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 53)
  - "From Hamburg to Basrah: Will an Old German Dream Become Reality?" Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 24: 54, Reel 31)
  - "Fuehrende Deutsche zur Wiedergutmachung," (Leading Germans on restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 11, 1963. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 55)
  - "Fuenf Jahre nachher," (Five years later), Mimeographed copies., August 1957. (Folder 24: 56, Reel 31)
  - "25 Jahre UNO," (25 years of the UN), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., August 21, 1970. (Folder 24: 57, Reel 31)
  - "Fuer eine schnelle und gerechte Wiedergutmachung. Eine Unterhaltung mit dem Ausschussvorsitzenden Martin Hirsch," (For a speedy and just restitution. A conversation with committee chairman M.H.), Aufbau, Printed copy., September 28, 1962. (Folder 24: 58, Reel 31)
  - "Fuer sein Land," (For his country), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., August 14, 1969. (Reel 31, Folder 24: 59)
  - "Die Geduldsprobe," (Test of patience), Aufbau, Printed copies., May 20, 1966. (Folder 24: 60, Reel 31)
  - "Gefahr der Konfrontation," (Danger of confrontation), Tagwacht, Printed copy., July 20, 1970. (Folder 24: 61, Reel 31)
  - "Die Gefahr im Osten," (Danger in the east), Die Menschenrechte, Printed copy., July 16, 1926. (Folder 24: 62, Reel 31)
  - "Die Gefahr von rechts..." (Danger on the right), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 14, 1968. (Folder 24: 63, Reel 31)
  - "Gefaehrdete Krankenkassebeitrags-Zuschuesse," (Jeopardized health insurance benefits), Aufbau, Printed copy and related material., December 26, 1969. (Folder 24: 64, Reel 31)
  - "Die Gefahren der Reaktion in den Vereinigten Staaten," (The dangers of reaction in the US), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., May 14, 1969. (Folder 24: 65, Reel 31)
  - "Gegen Extreme von rechts oder links," (Against extremes of right or left), Telegraf, Printed copy., April 17, 1966. (Folder 24: 66, Reel 31)
  - Gegenwart im Rueckblick: Festgabe fuer die juedische Gemeinde zu Berlin 25 Jahre nach dem Neubeginn, (The present in retrospect: presentation for the Jewish community in Berlin 25 years after its re-establishment). Final form published in Heidelberg, Lothar Stiehm, with Grossmann as co-editor and contributor., 1970
    - "Einfuehrung," (Introduction), Typescript (carbon copy)., July 1970 (Folder 25: 1, Reel 31)
    - "Die deutschen Juden auf der Linken," (German Jews on the left), Typescript and galley proofs. (Folder 25: 2, Reel 31)
    - Galley proofs and related material. (Reel 31, Folder 25: 3)
    - Page proofs. (Reel 31, Folder 25: 4)
    - Prospectus. (Reel 31, Folder 25: 5)
    - Reviews. (Reel 31, Folder 25: 6)
  - "Geht das Entschaedigungswerk zu Ende?" (Is the restitution effort close to completion?), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copies., June 14, 1968. (Reel 31, Folder 25: 7)
  - "Geht es mit der Wiedergutmachung vorwaerts?" (Is the restitution effort making progress?"), Mimeographed copy., February 21, 1961. (Reel 31, Folder 25: 8)
  - "Gelaehmt," (Paralyzed), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., August 29, 1968. (Folder 25: 9, Reel 31)
  - "George Ball on Bonn's Policy, a Continuing Discussion," German Information Center, Mimeographed copy., January 8, 1971. (Folder 25: 10, Reel 31)
  - "George Wallace ein Verbuendeter Nixons?" (G.W. an ally of Nixon?), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 25: 11, Reel 31)
  - "George Wallace Nutzniesser des Transport-problems der Schulkinder," (G.W. Beneficiary of the transportation problems of school children), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 25: 12, Reel 31)
  - "George Wallace siegt in Alabama," (G.W. wins in A.), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., June 10, 1970. (Reel 31, Folder 25: 13)
  - "Gerechtigkeit ist unteilbar," (Justice is indivisible), Aufbau, Printed copy and related material., July 3, 1970. (Folder 25: 14, Reel 31)
  - "Gerhart Seger, 70 Jahre," Aufbau, Printed copy., November 11, 1966. (Folder 25: 15, Reel 31)
  - "The German Dilemma," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 25: 16, Reel 32)
  - "The German-Israeli Agreement," South Atlantic Quarterly, Reprint., October 1954. (Folder 25: 17, Reel 32)
  - "The German-Israeli Relations, a Thorny Road," Typescript (carbon copy)., 1965. (Folder 25: 18, Reel 32)
  - "German-Jewish Relations: A Reappraisal," lecture, Theodor Herzl Institute, Typescript and related material., May 26, 1971. (Folder 25: 19, Reel 32)
  - "German-Polish Understanding from the Past to the Present," Typescript and photocopy. (Folder 25: 20, Reel 32)
  - "German Public Opinion Towards Restitution," Typescript., n.d. (Folder 25: 21, Reel 32)
  - "Germany and Restitution," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., May 7, 1956. (Folder 25: 22, Reel 32)
  - "Germany and Russia," Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 32, Folder 25: 23)
  - "Germany's Moral Crossroads," Congress Bi-Weekly, Printed copies., February 15, 1965. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 24)
  - Germany's Moral Debt, the German-Israel Agreement, by Grossmann, reviews. Printed and typescript copies. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 25)
  - "Gertrud Luckner," Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copies., May 2, 1958. (Folder 25: 26, Reel 32)
  - "Gertrud Luckner, 70 Jahre," Aufbau, Printed copies., September 25, 1970. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 27)
  - "Die Geschichte der deutsch-polnishce Verstaendigung," Die neue Gesellschaft, Typescript and reprint. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 28)
  - "Gesetz und Ordnung versus Establishment," (Law and order vs. the establishment), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., November 27, 1970. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 29)
  - "Der gestohlene Friedensnobelpreis," (The stolen Nobel Peace Prize), Deutsche Presse Agentur, Mimeographed copy., c. 1955. (Folder 25: 30, Reel 32)
  - "Getoese von Rechts in USA," (Upheaval on the right in the US), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 31)
  - "Gewalt vor Recht," (Force before law), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 32)
  - "Gewehre in ihren Haenden," (Weapons in their hands), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 29, 1969. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 33)
  - "Gewerkschafter gegen Nixon," (Unions against N.), Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 28, 1971. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 34)
  - "Das Gewissen der USA" (The conscience of the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy)., December 3, 1968. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 35)
  - "Das Gewissen entscheidet," (The conscience decides), Aufbau, Printed copy., September 10, 1965. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 36)
  - "Das Gewissen hat nicht entscheiden..." (Conscience did not decide), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 17, 1965. (Folder 25: 37, Reel 32)
  - "Das Gewissen und das Bundesentschaedigungsgesetz," (conscience and the German restitution law), Mimeographed copy., May 28, 1962. (Folder 25: 38, Reel 32)
  - "Gibt es ein deutsches Dilemma?" (Is there a German dilemma?) Die Mahnung, Mimeographed and typescript copies., January 1, 1960. (Reel 32, Folder 25: 39)